真高兴终于见到你了  哈罗德
So nice to finally meet you, Harold.
你叫我"根"好了
You can call me Root.
根带走芬奇时  杀死了
When she took Finch, Root killed
一名前情报部门人员  名叫艾丽西娅・考文
a former intelligence operative named Alicia Corwin.
你应该想办法弄明白我想要什么
You should be trying to figure out what I want
以及我们要去哪里
and where we're going.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
未来  哈罗德
The future, Harold.
我有芬奇的线索
I got a lead on Finch.
你知道我们的神秘女要去哪儿吗
You know where our mystery woman's headed?
不  但我知道了她从哪儿来的
No, but I think I found out where she's from.
收拾东西  卡特  我们要去德克萨斯
Pack your bags, Carter. We're going to Texas.
911  有什么紧急状况
911. What is your emergency?
你好  哪位
Hello, who is this?
是汉娜的事  那个失踪的女孩子
It's about Hanna, the girl who's gone missing.
-这是干嘛呢  -这话什么意思
- So what's this all about? - What do you mean?
我说过会请你们喝酒的
I promised you guys that round of drinks.
现在是早上八点
It's 8:00 am.
也就是说芬奇已经失踪24小时了
Which means Finch has already been gone 24 hours,
我们要把他找回来
but we're gonna get him back.
这里边是生鸡蛋吗
This have a raw egg in it?
酒精能杀死沙门氏菌
The alcohol will kill the salmonella.
那个女孩子方面有发现了吗  卡特
You find out anything on the girl, Carter?
有  1991年  14岁的汉娜・弗雷
Yeah. 1991, 14-year-old Hanna Frey
离开德克萨斯毕夏普的公立图书馆
walks out of the Public Library in Bishop, Texas,
就此消失了
never to be seen again.
她现在应该35岁了  应该就是她
She'd be 35 today. Seems about right.
那女孩就是现在的"根"  抓走了芬奇
That girl became Root, and now she's got Finch.
她从那之后就再也
Nothing else about her
没出现在国家执法部门数据库了  约翰
in any national law enforcement database since, John.
我得知道你是从哪里得来的消息
Look, I need to know where you're getting your information.
不能告诉你
I can't tell you that.
但是只要我们查清楚她的事
But we find out what happened to her,
-就能找到芬奇  -就这姑娘
- we find Finch. - This girl...
二十年杳无音信的
been gone 20 years without a trace.
你喝多久了这是
How long you been drinking?
我们要去德克萨斯毕夏普
We're going to Bishop, Texas,
查清楚汉娜・弗雷的事
to find out what happened to Hanna Frey.
那我呢
What about me?
我要你留在这里  莱奈尔
I need you to stay here, Lionel,
查艾丽西娅・考文被杀案
work the Alicia Corwin case.
查清楚为什么考文会来纽约
Find out why Corwin was in New York,
查清楚谁在插手这个案子
and find out who's messing with the case.
这个应该能帮上忙
Maybe this'll help.
你黑了我的手机
Did you just jack my phone?
恶意软件应用程序
It's a malware app.
温馨提示  要是有人
Little tip-- someone offers you a great deal
声称要为你提供伟哥超值优惠
on any sort of male-enhancement pill,
千万不要点击打开
don't click on it.
还有件事  你帮我照看一位朋友
Oh, another thing. I need you to look after a friend of mine.
小熊  还记得莱奈尔吗
Bear, remember Lionel?
考文案处理得如何了
Where are we on the Corwin mess?
只剩一点扫尾工作了
A few loose ends to clean up,
不过我倒不担心有证据被查到
but I wouldn't worry about the evidence trail.
毕竟  保管链都完了
Consider the chain of custody broken.
我们得查清楚她为什么来纽约
We need to find out what brought her to New York.
我想我查到她在这里的住址了
I think I have a lead on where she was staying in the city.
一定要第一个赶过去
Just make sure you get there first.
说不定那个疯子
No telling what kind of smoking gun
还留下了什么铁证
that nut job left lying around.
死掉的疯子
A dead nut job.
曾在丹顿・威克斯手下工作
Used to work for Denton Weeks.
威克斯那边我来处理
Let me worry about Weeks.
负责这案子的那位怎么样
What do we know about the assigned working the case?
不足为虑
I wouldn't sweat that too much.
那位绝非啥纽约精英
Not exactly New York's finest working on this one.
好了
Okay.
德克萨斯州  毕夏普
还好你打电话过来了
Lucky you called when you did.
猎鹿季刚刚开始  这一整周房间都被预定一空了
Deer season just started. Booked up solid for the week.
我可不要
Oh, I don't think so.
我们还要一间房
We're gonna need another room.
恐怕我无能为力了
Afraid I can't help you there.
停车场还有三辆房车排队
I've got three RVs backed up in the lot
等着有自来水的房间呢
looking for a room with running water.
谢谢  可以了
Thanks. This won't be a problem.
这到底要怎么睡啊
So what exactly are the sleeping arrangements?
我本来就没打算睡
Well, I don't plan on sleeping much.
就算要睡  浴缸也
And if I do, the bathtub will--
地板也不错
the floor will be fine.
我们去警局
Let's go down to the police station
调汉娜・弗雷的卷宗吧
and get ahold of that case file on Hanna Frey.
好的  等等
Okay. Wait.
我们先定下基本原则
Let's set up some ground rules here.
你保持低调  由我去
You keep a low profile and let me deal
跟当地执法部门谈  明白吗
with the local law enforcement, all right?
我正是为此才请你来的
That's why you're here.
涉及到1991年汉娜・弗雷的案子
It's regarding the Hanna Frey case back in '91.
是的女士  我记得很清楚
Yes, ma'am, I remember it well.
你怎么会对这案子有兴趣  警探贵姓
What's your interest in the case, Detective, uh...
卡特
Carter.
纽约布朗克斯区有个失踪案
I may have a missing person's case in the Bronx
手法与这起类似
that matches the MO.
一名小女孩从公立图书馆失踪了
A young girl went missing from a public library,
就像汉娜・弗雷一样
like Hanna Frey,
其中一名嫌犯曾住在德克萨斯
and one of my suspects used to live in Texas.
是吗  那嫌犯叫什么名字
Really? What's the suspect's name?
很遗憾  我无权透露姓名
Unfortunately, I'm not at liberty to share names.
案件仍在调查中
Still a developing case.
警长  我非常希望能
Sheriff, I'd really just like to
看一下汉娜的卷宗
have a look at Hanna's case file.
是啊  我也非常希望能
Yeah, well, I'd really like to
知道那嫌犯的名字
have the name of this suspect,
看能不能帮我们破了这起
seeing as how it might help break a case
困扰我们局二十年的案子
that's haunted this department some 20 years.
好吧  很遗憾
Right. Unfortunately,
我的上司并没有批准联合调查
my loo hasn't signed off on a joint investigation.
有何不可呢
I don't see why not.
他都把你派到这里了  不是吗
He sent you all the way down here, didn't he?
请签收
Sign here, please.
你好啊
Well, hello.
丹今天怎么没来
What happened to Dan today?
-他换路线了  -真可惜
- He got rerouted. - Well, that is too bad.
我能用一下洗手间吗
Mind if I use your restroom?
请自便  过了大厅
Help yourself. It's just down the hall
右边就是
and to the left.
好吧  这样吧
All right, I'll tell you what.
不如你把你上司的名字和电话号码给我
Why don't you give me the name and number of your loo,
我亲自打电话给他
and I'll call him myself.
不行吗  那真可惜
No? Well, that's too bad.
那祝你在毕夏普过得愉快
Well, I hope you enjoy your stay here in Bishop.
狩猎捕鱼  最佳所在
Hunting and fishing, second to none.
搞什么
What the--
是我想的那东西吗
is that what I think it is?
要跟的线索很多
Plenty of leads to follow up on.
给
Here.
我不知道你刚才干了什么
I don't know what you just did,
但这不是
but this is not the way--
曾经有人打过911报警电话声称
There was even a 911 call from someone claiming
看到汉娜在那晚上了一辆车
they saw Hanna get into the car that night.
他们还记下了车牌  但没查出来什么
They gave a plate number too, but it didn't check out.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得我们该从头开始
I think we start from the beginning.
我们得去找最后见到汉娜的人聊聊
We need to talk to whoever saw Hanna last.
她还活着  卡特
She's still out there, Carter.
我告诉你  那女孩就是现在的"根"
I'm telling you, that girl became Root.
搜索系统管理员
马里兰州惠尔顿
长点路16号
获取麦克风
马里兰州惠尔顿
长点路16号
多么神奇  我们能让苹果更加完美
Amazing. We've managed to perfect the apple--
基因修改版本使其永远不会变色
a genetically modified version that never goes brown.
但是  我们却仍没有升级人类
And yet, we still haven't upgraded human beings.
人类的发展已经停滞不前了  哈罗德
The human race has stalled out, Harold.
在我看来
And from what I've seen,
大多数已经腐烂透了
most of it is rotten to the core.
哈罗德  多么宅心仁厚
Oh, Harold, generous to a fault.
总是任由别人领取属于你的功劳
Always letting someone else take credit for your work.
我随处都能认出你独有的代码
I'd recognize your code anywhere.
如此的  优雅
It's so...elegant.
-那就放过它吧  -我告诉你了
- Then let it be. - I told you,
我不是想控制你的机器
I don't want to control your machine.
那我们在这干什么
Then why are we here?
我们在这是为了观察另一种代码
We're here to observe another kind of code.
错误代码
The bad code.
很明显  我们对人性的观点有所不同
Clearly, we differ in our views of humanity.
是吗  那为什么你身为
Do we? Then why are you the father
创世纪智慧体之父
of a seismic shift in intelligence,
却被迫隐姓埋名生活在恐惧之中呢
forced to live in fear and anonymity?
你根本不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
我了解  哈罗德
Oh, but I do, Harold.
你拱手卖出了全世界
You're the man who sold the world.
只是卖给了错误的人
Just to the wrong people.
我会获取机器的权限  哈罗德
I will get access to the machine, Harold.
要么你告诉我怎么做
And either you can show me how to do that,
要么这个可怜虫告诉我
or this sad specimen will.
丹顿・威克斯
Denton Weeks--
买了你机器的人
the man you sold the machine to.
你们俩只有一个能离开这里
One of you will walk out of here
进入下一阶段的冒险
onto the next stage of our adventure.
我真希望是你  哈罗德
I do hope it's you, Harold.
第二季 第二集
疑犯追踪
我当然记得
Of course I remember.
我倒希望自己能忘记
I only wish I could forget.
汉娜是个聪明的女孩  不太喜欢跟人沟通
Hanna was a bright girl. Mostly kept to herself.
你注意到那天晚上她有什么不对劲吗
Did you notice anything off about her that night?
没有
Not really.
她就坐在那边的电脑那里
She was at the computers over there.
就和她往常一样
Like she was almost every night.
那时还没有互联网
We didn't have internet back then,
只是几台电脑和一些游戏
just a couple of PCs and a few games.
当然都是教育类的
Educational, of course.
获取数据
主体
弗雷  汉娜
俄勒冈之旅
你可以
1、开始游戏
2、学习内容
3、游戏十强
4、关闭声音
你想选择哪一个？
你为警方提供了一份那晚
You gave the police a list of everyone
在图书馆的人员名单
who was in the library that night?
是的  谢谢
Yes. Thank you.
那时图书馆快闭馆了
The library was about to close.
人们在陆续离开
Everyone was leaving.
你又找到本史蒂芬・金的小说
I see you found the new Stephen King.
现代恐怖小说大师  《肖申克的救赎》作者
上一本我很喜欢
I really enjoyed the last one.
谢谢  芭芭拉
Thanks, Barbara.
该死
Damn it.
你输了
汉娜葬于此
又死在痢疾这题上了
Death by dysentery again.
这游戏多傻啊  汉娜
That game's so dumb, Hanna.
真不明白你为什么要玩
I don't see why you play it.
因为我就要去俄勒冈了
Because I'm gonna get to Oregon.
图书馆十分钟后闭馆
The library will be closing in ten minutes.
请把你想借阅的书带到柜台登记
Bring any books you'd like to check out to the counter.
-回见  -拜拜
- See ya. - Bye.
《献给阿尔吉侬的花束》
汉娜借了几本书
Hanna checked out a couple of books.
-谢谢  -晚安  汉娜
- Thank you. - Good night, Hanna.
然后她就消失了
And then she was gone.
那是她最后一次出现吗
That's the last time anyone ever saw her?
我完全不知道有事发生了
I had no idea there was something to worry about
直到兰德里警长
until I got a call from Sheriff Landry
半夜打电话告诉我
in the middle of the night saying
汉娜没有回家
Hanna never made it home.
她父母还住在这附近吗
Her parents still live here?
她母亲几年前去世了
Her mother passed a few years ago.
我时不时还能看到她父亲
I still see her father every once in a while.
-女士  -谢谢
- Ma'am. - Thank you.
你不相信汉娜还活着
You don't believe Hanna could still be alive.
那是我妻子的诅咒
That was my wife's curse.
拒绝相信汉娜已经死了
Refused to believe Hanna was gone.
认为她还活在某处
Thought she was still out there somewhere.
你知道那天发生了什么吗
Do you have any idea what happened?
我当然知道
Of course I do.
镇上每个人都知道发生了什么
Everyone in town knows what happened.
警察审讯了那个混蛋
The cops interrogated that son of a bitch
整整两天
for over two days.
科迪・格雷森
Cody Grayson?
那不是他第一次跟踪她回家了
It wasn't the first time he followed her home,
但没有找到尸体他们就无法定罪
but they can't prove a damn thing without a body.
然后有一天晚上  我和我哥哥
Then one night, me and my brother
去了科迪家
paid Cody a visit.
你们找到答案了吗
Did you get the truth?
那个假惺惺的混蛋说他从没碰过她
The smirking son of a bitch said he never touched her.
说她可能是为逃离混蛋父亲而离家出走了
Said she probably ran to escape her jerk of a father.
科迪后来怎样了
What ever happened to Cody?
听说他每天晚上都在野猪酒吧喝得酩酊大醉
Most nights I hear he's rotting his guts out at the Razorback.
谢谢
Thank you.
有人在汉娜失踪后联系过你吗
Anyone ever reach out to you after Hanna was gone?
有信件或是信息可以帮助我们的吗
Any correspondence or information that might help us?
只有一些信用卡的宣传邮件
Nothing except some credit card junk mail
一年会寄来几次
a couple times a year.
是以汉娜的名字吗
But they were in Hanna's name?
她有信用卡或是银行账户吗
Did she have a credit card or a bank account?
没有  她那时还未成年
No, she was still a minor.
你还有那些信吗
You got one of those letters?
我几天前刚扔了一封
I threw out another one a couple of days ago.
可能还在垃圾桶里
Probably still in the trash.
你觉得艾丽西娅・考文没把酒店
Hey, you think it's odd that Alicia Corwin didn't have
钥匙带在身上奇怪不
her hotel key on her person?
也许她落在酒店了
Maybe she left it at the hotel.
也许她把所有东西都落在酒店了
Maybe she left everything at the hotel.
因为这不是唯一一个
Because that's not the only discrepancy
证据清单上列明有
between what's listed in evidence
其实里边却没有的东西
and what's actually here.
是啊  弹道报告也被损坏了
Yeah, ballistics report was corrupted too.
有人是迫切想掩盖掉这案子啊
Someone really wants this to go away.
找到那个人  也许就能找到答案
You find that person, maybe you'll get some answers.
弗斯科  这案子涉及的人  你要小心
And, Fusco, be careful who you read in on the case.
我会的  一会儿再跟你说
Yeah. All right. I'll talk with you later.
好的
Okay.
汉娜・弗雷
瞧那西装男
Look at the guy in the suit.
-找科迪・格雷森  -华尔街仔
- Cody Grayson. - Hey, Wall Street.
你迷路了吗
You lost?
吧台最里边
End of the bar.
-瞧那家伙  -谁啊
- Look at this guy. - Who's that?
你好啊  科迪
Hello, Cody.
我认识你吗
I know you?
你认识我要找的人
You know someone I'm looking for.
汉娜・弗雷
Hanna Frey.
你是记者还是联调局的
You a journalist or a fed?
-都不是  -很好
- Neither. - Good.
-放开他  -给敬酒不吃
- Get off of him! - I asked you nicely.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好 紫玉 丢丢曳 芒果妖怪 二摆舞 天朝直属
时间轴：凌晨相见 菜六水
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监：阿好
我们重新来过
Let's try that again.
你对汉娜・弗雷做了什么
What did you do with Hanna Frey?
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say, man,
说我宰了她  把她丢到沼泽里了吗
that I cut her up, dumped her in the swamp?
不管你想怎么做
Ain't nothing you can do
这地方的人早对我做过更狠的了
this town hasn't already done worse.
汉娜怎么了  她在哪儿
What happened to Hanna? Where is she?
我要是知道  没准儿我这只眼就不会瞎了
If I knew, maybe I'd still be able to see out of this eye.
我来猜猜  科迪・格雷森
Let me guess-- Cody Grayson.
我还以为能请他喝一杯呢
I thought I'd buy him a round.
交朋友啊
Making friends, huh?
你这样不可能得到真相
Yeah, you'll never get the truth out of anybody like that.
我已经得到了  不是他做的
I already did. He didn't do it.
这点我就可以告诉你了
I could have told you that.
看来你对汉娜・弗雷的事说对了
Looks like you might be right about Hanna Frey.
有她名字的宣传邮件
Junk mail with her name on it.
做了个信用调查
Ran a credit check.
发现了有个账户是用她名字开的户
Discovered a bank account opened in her name
在93年  她失踪两年后
back in '93, two years after she disappeared.
所以除非说汉娜从坟墓出来显灵了  否则
So either Hanna's communicating from beyond the grave, or...
她还活着
She's still alive.
能不能拜托你停手
Can you please make this stop?
在头套里再待上一个小时
Another hour in that hood,
我说什么他就会信什么
and he'll believe anything I say.
多神奇啊  人类的大脑
Amazing how easily the human brain
多容易被操控啊
can be manipulated.
不过这个你知道的  不是吗  丹顿
But you know that, don't you, Denton?
国防部最高机密备忘录批准授权
A top-secret DOD memo authorizing
高强度审讯手段
enhanced interrogation techniques,
包括  巴勒斯坦吊刑
including "Palestinian hanging,"
就是你正在享受的这种
which you are currently enjoying.
最后是谁的签名
Whose signature is at the end?
-怎么  是你啊  -求你
- Why, it's yours. - Please...
水
water.
对不起  不被允许
Sorry, not allowed.
除非你告诉我  我想知道的东西
Unless you tell me what I want to know.
女士  我不懂你在说什么
Lady, I have no idea what you're talking about.
我是一名白宫律师
I'm a White House lawyer.
我只签署文件  并没有读
I sign documents. I don't read 'em.
求你  看在上帝的份上  放我下来
Please, for the love of God, let me down.
除非你告诉我机器在哪里
If you tell me where the machine is.
什么机器
What machine?
他造的那台机器
The machine he built.
内森・英格拉姆以一美元价格卖给你的那台机器
The machine Nathan Ingram sold you for one US dollar.
你知道它在哪儿
You know where it is.
我什么都不知道  我发誓
I don't know anything. I swear.
说真的  哈罗德  人们为什么总是
Really, Harold, why do men always seek
不见棺材不落泪呢
to delay the inevitable?
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
我吗
Me?
你以为我受过创伤  有童年阴影吗
You think I was damaged? Some childhood trauma?
我是个甜心噢
I'm so sweet.
放他下来
Let him down.
求你了
Please.
既然你求我了
Well, you did say please.
水  求你了
Water, please.
这场戏要转场到公路上继续了
Oh, we need to get this show on the road.
鉴于你刚喝了200升硫喷妥钠[吐真剂]
And since you just drank half a pint of sodium pentothal,
我正好有时间去给车加个油
that gives me time to go gas up the car.
等我回来的时候
By the time I get back,
你应该准备好吐出你小脑袋里的所有东西了
you'll be ready to spill everything in your little head.
你
You.
我认识你
I know you.
你和内森・英格拉姆共事过
You work with Nathan Ingram.
你得帮我逃走
You have to help me get free.
我们面临着最大的问题
We have a major problem.
不能让她获取机器的权限
She cannot get access to the machine.
假设汉娜逃跑了  几年后
Assuming Hanna runs away, a couple years later,
她在路易斯安那州拉斐特市出现
she winds up in Lafayette, Louisiana,
开了个账户  存入了十万块
opens an account, 100 grand is paid in,
之后的三周内一直在取现
withdrawn in cash over the next three weeks
直到账户关闭
until the account is closed.
十万块
100 grand.
一个离家出走的16岁女孩哪里弄到的钱
Where does a 16-year-old runaway get all that money?
约瑟・巴瑞亚  现在正处于终身监禁中
Jose Barilla, currently serving 17 life sentences
罪名是贩毒及谋杀
for drug trafficking and murder.
那钱从他账户电汇出去的
The money was electronically transferred out of his account.
你说过这个"根"擅长电脑
You did say this Root woman was good with computers.
是的
Yes, I did.
但这个账户把我们引向了哪里
But where does the account lead us?
就是这儿
Right back here.
这是个共同署名的账户
There was a co-signatory on the account.
一个叫特伦特・拉塞尔的人
A guy named Trent Russell.
本地地址  就在毕夏普
Local address, right here in Bishop.
名字听上去很耳熟
Name sounds familiar.
没错  他在目击者名单上
Yeah, he was on the witness list,
就在她从图书馆消失的那天晚上
in the library that night she disappeared.
你还有那个地址吗
You still got that address?
是谁
Who is it?
拉塞尔夫人  我是卡特警探
Mrs. Russell, it's Detective Carter.
你丈夫在家吗
Is your husband at home?
拉塞尔夫人
Mrs. Russell?
我是
Uh, yes.
特伦特・拉塞尔是你丈夫吗
Trent Russell is your husband?
我们能和他谈谈吗
Can we talk to him?
特伦特15年前就去世了
Trent passed away almost 15 years ago.
我很遗憾
Oh, I'm so sorry.
-我们能进来吗  -请进
- Can we come in? - Oh, come in.
我们结婚没几年
We were only married a few years.
我们在图书馆认识的
We met at the library.
特伦特是读书俱乐部的成员
Trent was a member of the monthly book club.
我非常想念他
I miss him so much.
他怎么死的
How did he die?
太可怕了
It was awful.
他被袭击了
He was attacked.
-枪击致死  -知道凶手是谁吗
- Shot to death. - They know who did it?
警察说似乎是毒贩所为
Police said it looked like a drug killing,
边境过来的败类
some trash from over the border,
但一直没抓住他们
but never caught them.
特伦特是银行贷款职员
Trent was a bank loan officer.
他是否卷入了洗钱活动
Is it possible he got caught up in money laundering?
不  他是好人
No, he was a good man.
那是搞错了
It was just a mistake.
他认识汉娜・弗雷多久了
How long did he know Hanna Frey?
汉娜  他不认识
Hanna? He didn't.
那你要怎么解释这个
Then how do you explain this?
他以汉娜的名义开了户
He signed for a bank account in her name
就在她失踪两年之后
two years after she disappeared.
一定是哪里搞错了
This must be some kind of mistake.
对  就跟他被谋杀一样
Yeah, just like his murder.
介意我们四处看看吗
You mind if we look around the place?
我介意  你们得离开了
Yes, I do. You need to leave now.
卡特
Carter!
那通911报警电话
That 911 call.
看到汉娜上车的目击者
The witness who saw Hanna get into the car--
说了个车牌号
there was a license plate.
等等
Hold on.
报警人说  是汉娜的事  那个失踪的女孩子
Caller: It's about Hanna, the girl who's gone missing.
我看到她上了一辆车
I think I saw her get into a car
就在图书馆外面
outside the library.
"接线员问到车的品牌
"The operator asked about the make of car,
"但打电话的人只记得
"but the only thing the caller can remember
车牌是  925ESK"
is the license plate-- 925 ESK."
925EFK
925 EFK.
报警人记错了一个字母
The caller got one digit wrong.
或者接线员记错了
Or the operator did.
这就是那辆车吗
Are we saying this is the car?
特伦特・拉塞尔绑架了汉娜・弗雷
Trent Russell kidnapped Hanna Frey?
也许  也许拉塞尔抓住了她  但她逃了
Maybe--maybe Russell took her, but she escaped.
然后去复仇
She got her revenge.
为什么这么说
How can you say that?
因为账户是以拉塞尔的名义开的
Because of the bank account in Russell's name.
这是"根"的行事风格  她陷害他
It's how Root works. She set him up.
她从毒贩那里偷了十万块
She stole 100 grand from a drug dealer.
毒贩发现钱不见时
When he found out it was missing,
要追杀的人是拉塞尔
the person he went after was Russell.
拉塞尔否认  但没用
Russell denies it, but it's useless.
账户上写的是他的名字
His name is on the account.
而另一个名字是
The only other name is that of a girl
一个两年前死去的女孩
who's been dead for two years.
只可能是他在说谎
He has to be lying.
求你们了  求你们了
Please, please!
所以绑架汉娜的家伙
So the man who kidnapped Hanna
在停车场被枪杀
gets gunned down in a parking lot.
而受害人却消失无踪
And his victim is in the wind,
还拿走十万美金
100 grand the richer.
是"根"  一定是"根"
It's Root. It has to be Root.
我们得搜查这栋房子
We need to search that house.
我们得通知警长
We need to call the sheriff.
我们得走正路处理这案子  约翰
We need to handle this the right way, John.
她很快就会回来
She'll come back soon.
我知道你不愿相信我  你不了解我
I know you're reluctant to trust me--you don't know me--
我了解你  威克斯先生
I do know who you are, Mr. Weeks.
你曾试图黑进机器
You tried to hack the machine.
我试过  那是我的工作
I certainly tried. It was my job.
我得测试它的极限  确认它是否安全
I had to test its limits, see if it was safe.
但我们预想了所有的危机
But in all of our crisis scenarios,
却没料到会这样
we never envisioned this.
会有人找上我们中的一个
That someone would get to one of us.
她不会通过我找到机器
She won't get to the machine through me.
但你要知道  如果你不帮我逃跑
But you must see that if you don't help me get free,
我们就会失去机器
we will lose the machine.
我要怎么做
What can I do?
那把刀
The knife.
想办法推过来
Try to push it to me.
住手
Stop.
-住手  -别担心
- Stop it! - Don't worry!
别担心  我不会杀她的
Don't worry, I'm not gonna kill her.
至少得先查清她知道什么
At least not until I've found out what she knows.
那么  英格拉姆的信息技术人员
So... Ingram's little IT guy.
我们一直都怀疑那西装笔挺的笨蛋
We always suspected the idiot in the tux
不可能一个人搞成功
couldn't have done it on his own.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我想知道  你所知道的
I want to know what you know.
约翰
John.
《献给阿尔吉侬的花束》
Flowers For Algernon.
是汉娜那天晚上从图书馆借出的书
The book Hanna checked out that night at the library.
你卧室里有十六本
16 copies hidden in your bedroom.
哪来的
Where'd you get 'em?
送过来的
They just come...
每年都有
every year.
每年的同一天
Every year on the same date.
-哪天  -四月十五号
- What date? - April 15th.
汉娜失踪的日子
The day Hanna disappeared.
它们从全国各地被送过来
They just arrive from all over the country.
没有留言  没有寄件人
No note, no sender.
好像有人就是想折磨我
Like someone just wants to be cruel.
卡特
Carter.
最近寄过来的书里面有东西
The most recent book did have something.
我去找是谁买的
I'm gonna find out who bought it.
你待在这里
You stay here.
她还没全招
She's not done yet.
她是真把我逼急了
She really sent me over the edge.
你有什么计划  威克斯先生
So what's your plan, Mr. Weeks?
收拾好这里
Tidy this up,
找几个真正的专家审问这个贱人
get some real experts to question this bitch.
但既然你特别想隐姓埋名
But since anonymity means a lot to you,
而且又帮了我
and because you helped me,
我会放你走
I'm gonna let you go wherever you want.
只要回答一个问题
Just one more question.
她能成功吗
Can she get to it?
我得知道它是否安全
I need to know if it's safe.
而你可以告诉我答案
You are the one man who can tell me.
拜托
Please.
无法远程修改
It cannot be altered remotely.
如果要做改动
If anyone wanted to change anything,
必须接触到服务器吗
they'd have to have physical access to the servers?
对
That's right.
那么只要位置没暴露
So if the location is hidden,
机器就是安全的
the machine is safe.
我只需要这些
That's all I need.
很荣幸最终见到了你
It's been an honor to meet you...at last.
我什么来着  哈罗德
What did I say, Harold?
错误代码
Bad code.
他来了
Hey, here he comes.
听说你住这儿  伙计
Heard you were staying here, buddy.
现在没时间  伙计们
Not now, fellas.
我觉得是时候重赛了
I think it's time for a rematch.
别以为你能再把我打趴下
Don't think you're gonna sucker punch me again. Oh!
我是斯蒂尔斯警探  纽约警局凶案组的
This is Detective Stills, NYPD homicide.
我想询问关于你在四月初
I'm calling about a book you sold
售出的一本书
at the beginning of April,
《献给阿尔吉侬的花束》
Flowers For Algernon.
我要追踪买家
I need to trace the buyer.
911  有什么紧急状况
911. What is your emergency?
是汉娜的事
It's about Hanna,
那个失踪的女孩子
the girl who's gone missing.
我看到她上了一辆车  就在图书馆外面
I think I saw her get into a car outside the library.
什么样的车
What sort of car?
不知道  一辆暗色的车
I don't know. It was a dark car.
你还记得其他什么吗
Do you remember anything else?
是的  汽车牌照
Yes, the license plate.
925EFK
925EFK.
就这样
It goes on.
女孩被问及姓名  但不肯透露
The girl was asked but wouldn't give her name.
然后她挂断了
Then she hung up.
芭拉知道是谁  是吗
Barb knows who it is... don't you?
是萨姆・格罗夫斯
It's Sam Groves.
她那晚和汉娜一起在图书馆
She was in the library that night with Hanna.
她是汉娜的朋友吗
She was friends with Hanna?
汉娜挺照顾她
Hanna looked out for her.
《献给阿尔吉侬的花束》
Flowers For Algernon.
你该读读
You should read it.
写得很棒
It's awesome.
可恶  又死在痢疾这题上了
Damn it. Death by dysentery again.
这游戏多傻啊  汉娜
That game's so dumb, Hanna.
真不明白你为什么要玩
I don't see why you play it.
因为我就要去俄勒冈了
'cause I'm gonna get to Oregon.
图书馆十分钟后闭馆
The library will be closing in ten minutes.
请把你想借阅的书带到柜台登记
Bring any books you'd like to check out to the counter.
-回见  -拜拜
- See ya. - Bye.
萨姆12岁  很可爱的孩子
Sam was 12. Funny kid.
和她母亲一起住在镇外
Lived with her mom outside town.
她母亲身体不太好
Mom wasn't well.
可能因为这  她总在图书馆转悠
I guess that's why she always hung around the library.
为什么你确定是萨姆打的电话
Why are you sure it was Sam made the call?
还有其他女孩
There were other girls there.
-是萨姆  -你怎么知道
- It was Sam. - How do you know?
因为她跟我说了同样的话
Because she told me the same thing.
她说她见到汉娜上了一辆车
She said she saw Hanna get into a car.
芭拉  为什么你不告诉我
Barb, why didn't you tell me?
因为萨姆看到了谁在车里
Because Sam saw who was in the car.
而且她告诉了你  是吗
And she told you, didn't she?
她说
She said...
她觉得是拉塞尔先生
she thought it was Mr. Russell.
为什么你什么都不说
Why in the hell didn't you say anything?
我说了  我说了
I did. I did say something...
对她说的
to her.
我说她是个讨厌的  想引人注意的小屁孩
I told her she was a nasty, attention-seeking brat,
我简直不敢相信她会
and I couldn't believe she'd think
把拉塞尔先生想得那么坏
such a terrible thing about somebody like Mr. Russell,
他对我们小镇
who'd done so much for this town
我们图书馆  我们所有的孩子贡献巨大
and the library and all the children.
我让她闭上她那骗人的臭嘴
And then I told her to keep her lying little mouth shut.
为什么
Why?
因为我当时爱上了特伦特・拉塞尔
Because I was in love with Trent Russell,
我无法相信他会做这种事
and I couldn't believe he'd do such a thing.
那你现在信了吗
What do you believe now?
庭院吗
The patio?
他重修了
He redid it.
就在汉娜消失后两周
Two weeks after Hanna disappeared.
我是斯蒂尔斯警探  纽约警局的
Yes, this is Detective Stills, NYPD.
调查一起儿童失踪案件
Calling in connection to a missing-child case.
有一笔存款从你们银行的帐户转账到
A transfer was made from an account at your bank
一间位于西雅图的书店
to a bookstore in Seattle.
帐户名是冯・诺依曼
Account name was Von Neumann.
现代电子计算机之父
后四位数  4253
Last four digits, 4253.
伙计  我们不想惹麻烦
Hey, buddy, uh, no trouble.
就想来拿我们的东西  行不
We just need to get our stuff, you hear?
-警察办案  -没事了
- Police business. - We're good.
是的  我在听
Yes, I'm here.
找到了
Found something.
《献给阿尔吉侬的花束》
同样的书
Same book.
我需要查阅信用卡的最近使用记录
Yes, I need to check for recent activity
持卡人名叫戴森
on a credit card in the name of Dyson.
马里兰州惠尔顿的加油站
Gas station in Relton, Maryland?
清晨四点
Just after 4:00 am.
大约三小时前
About three hours ago.
找到了
Gotcha.
你知道我会帮他  是吗
You knew I'd help him, didn't you?
你让他攻击你  拿走你的枪
You let him beat you up, take your gun.
全是你安排好的
You planned the whole thing.
这就是你托付机器的人
That's who you gave your machine to.
暴力而又平庸
Violent and predictable people.
但你得了解  我站在你这边
But you must see I'm on your side.
-我根本没有站边  -你懂我的意思
- I'm not on any side. - You know what I mean.
我是你这辈子最好的朋友  最好的支柱
I am the best friend, the best support,
最好的搭档
the best partner you will ever have.
而且肯定是最有趣的
And definitely the most fun.
你不是
No.
你比威克斯还坏  你比所有人都坏
You're worse than Weeks. You're worse than all of them.
我宁愿死也不会把机器交给你
I'd rather die than give you the machine,
请你杀了我吧
so please kill me now.
至少死了就不用再听你说话了
At least I won't have to listen to you anymore.
你太累了
You're tired...
我也流血了
and I'm bloody.
我要去清理一下
I'm gonna go clean up.
卡特  你开租来的车吧
Carter, you can keep the rental.
有人借给了我一辆货车
Guys are lending me a truck.
为什么床上有个十字弩
Why is there a crossbow on the bed?
说来话长  不过我们现在是朋友了
Long story, but we're friends now.
得走了
Gotta go.
我订了加尔维斯敦一架私人飞机
Got a line on a private jet in Galveston.
-你要去哪  -回东部去
- Where are you going? - Back east. Look...
这本书指向了一家书店
this book led us to a bookstore,
一家银行  一家银行  一家银行  一张信用卡
to a bank, to a bank, to a bank, to a credit card,
这张卡约三小时前在马里兰州刷过
which was used in Maryland about three hours ago.
是根  汉娜就是根
It's Root. Hanna is Root.
她还活着  我知道她在哪
She's alive, and I know where she is.
她不是汉娜
She's not Hanna.
汉娜被埋到地下了  约翰
Hanna's in the ground, John.
她已经死了
She's dead.
她没能逃出拉塞尔的魔掌
She never did get away from Russell.
那是谁干的
Then who'd do this?
谁寄出了这些书  害死了拉塞尔
Who sent the books, got Russell killed?
汉娜的父亲给我的
Hanna's father gave it to me.
她名叫萨姆・格罗夫斯  是汉娜的朋友
Her name's Sam Groves. She was Hanna's friend.
她看到那晚汉娜上了拉塞尔的车
She saw Hanna get into Russell's car that night.
她告诉了芭拉  打了911
She told Barb, called 911,
但没人相信她的话
but nobody would listen.
她现在在哪
Where is she now?
她是独女
Only child.
母亲在大约10年前去世
Her mother died about ten years ago.
萨姆从此离开小镇  杳无音讯
So Sam left town, was never heard from again.
如果说谁是根  那肯定是她
If anybody's Root, it's gotta be her.
是她带走了芬奇
Then she's the one who took Finch.
我知道她在哪儿  我这就去追她
I know where she is. I'm going after her.
你赢了
这家伙是谁
Who is this guy?
强 制 配 对
成 功
我找到考文的隐藏点了
Looks like I found Corwin's hideaway.
成功了  用你们荷兰语怎么说
Hey, it worked. How do you say that in Dutch?
什么都没有
Nothing here.
因为人家抢先你一步了  聪明小子
'cause they beat you to it, smart guy.
别管了  我们还有更大的麻烦
Forget it, we got a bigger problem.
丹顿・威克斯  他消失了
Denton Weeks-- he's disappeared.
所有的电话都不接
He's not answering any of his phones.
有线索吗
You got any leads?
威克斯似乎有个小三
It seems Weeks had a woman on the side.
-蹲下  -茱莉・戴文波特
- Get down. - Julie Davenport.
看起来  他们经常偷跑到华盛顿外的爱巢
Apparently, they used to sneak off to her love shack outside of DC.
找出来
Just find it.
抱歉我花了很长时间
Sorry I took so long.
低剂量镇静剂
A mild sedative.
抱歉  不过我需要你更
I apologize, but I need you to be a little more...
听话一点
amenable.
信用卡服务中心
信用记录报告
我好像低估了
It seems I underestimated
信用卡服务中心
信用记录报告
你那位偏激的朋友
your knuckle-dragging friend.
不知道他是怎么找到这里的
How he got there I do not know.
你的机器在帮他吗  你觉得呢
Did the machine help him, do you think?
我们可以在路上探讨一下
Something for us to discuss on our journey.
希望你喜欢火车
I hope you like trains.
来吧  哈罗德
Come on, Harold.
最后一个问题  之后我会放了你
One more question, and then I'll leave you alone.
机器在哪
Where's the machine?
这回  可是上膛的
This time, it is loaded.
快说  你把机器藏哪了
Now, where did you move the machine?
我告诉你  我不知道
I'm telling you, I don't know.
等等  2009年7月12日
Wait. July 12, 2009,
它被装箱放上火车
It was boxed up and put on a train.
这么大量的服务器  当然需要用火车
With that amount of servers, of course it was a train.
-开向哪里  -从得梅因出发
- But a train to where? - It started in Des Moines,
后来转上联合太平洋铁路
then it was transferred to Union Pacific Railway,
开往盐湖城
bound for Salt Lake City.
我知道的就这么多
And that's all I know.
开了个好头
That's a start.
你不知道自己招惹了什么
You have no idea what you're getting into.
哈罗德
Harold...
你以为我会忘记掐掉电话线吗
did you think I'd forget to disconnect the phones?
我们走
Off we go.
我刚到马里兰  现在在加油站
I just landed in Maryland. I'm at a gas station.
她今早来过这里
She was here this morning.
我试着联系你好几个钟头了
I've been trying to reach you for hours.
找到什么了  弗斯科
Have you got something, Fusco?
我觉得带走你朋友的那妞
I think the broad who took your friend
同时还在追查丹顿・威克斯
is also going after a guy by the name of Denton Weeks,
他和考文隶属于同一类政府部门
who's in the same type of government business as Corwin was,
他失踪了
and he's missing.
联调局的人正在到处找他
The feds are flying around trying to find him.
知道他们查向哪里吗
You know where they're looking?
看起来  他女朋友
Apparently, he's got a girlfriend
在华盛顿城外有个别墅
who's got a cottage outside of DC.
我只查到了名字  茱莉・戴文波特
All I got is a name-- Julie Davenport.
搜索马里兰州惠尔顿
Search property records in Relton, Maryland,
茱莉・戴文波特名下的不动产
for a Julie Davenport.
我去看看火车有没有晚点  哈罗德
I just want to see if the train's on time, Harold.
记得我们之前说好的吗
Can I remind you of our deal?
敢乱来  无辜者就会受伤
Try anything, innocent people get hurt.
敲击代码  芬奇  真的吗
Tap code. Finch... really?
火车站
Train station.
从巴尔的摩开往盐湖城的
The outbound train with direct service
直达列车马上就要从
from Baltimore to Salt Lake City
七号站台出发
will be departing from track seven.
你会喜欢西部的  哈罗德
You'll like the west, Harold.
更少的人  更广阔的天空
Fewer people, bigger skies,
更多的思考空间
more space to think.
他怎么找到我们的
How did he find us?
你错了  他证明你错了
Because you're wrong. He proves you're wrong.
并非所有人都是错误代码
Not all humans are bad code.
你帮了他
You helped him.
我告诉过你要是你试图逃跑会怎么样
I told you what would happen if you tried to get away.
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me, sir.
有什么可以帮到您  女士
Can I help you, ma'am?
救命
Help!
有人开枪
Shooters!
别动  别动
Don't move. Don't move.
我中枪了吗
Am I hit?
应该没有
I don't think so.
对不起  拖了这么久
Sorry it took so long.
我都没有期待你来找我  里瑟先生
I really didn't intend for you to come and find me, Mr. Reese.
还有其他人需要你的帮助
There are other people that need your help.
你拯救过我那么一两次  哈罗德
Well, you saved my life once or twice, Harold.
我得回报一下才公平
Seemed only fair I return the favor.
你好
Hey.
你也好  狗呢
Hey, yourself. Where's the dog?
神奇小子带走了
Wonder Boy came and took him.
我们的眼镜朋友找回来了
So we got our friend with the glasses back, huh?
对啊  找回来了
Yeah, we did.
请你喝一杯
Buy you a drink?
只要里面没鸡蛋就行
Long as it don't have egg in it.
哈罗德  这是小熊
Harold, meet Bear.
很遗憾  我的公寓有严格的政策  不能养狗
Unfortunately, my apartment has a strict policy regarding dogs.
我也有严格的政策  别碰珍贵的初版书
I have a strict policy regarding rare first editions.
也就是说  不要吃掉它们
Namely, don't eat them.
小熊  [荷兰语]放下
Bear, laat vallen.
阿西莫夫
Asimov.
科幻小说大师  特别是人工智能方面  "机器人三定律"提出者
它有相当昂贵的品味
He has expensive taste.
我们肯定能相处愉快
I'm sure we'll get along.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
我欠你一次
I owe you a debt.
打扰你们了吗  约翰
Is this a bad time, John?
我想谢谢你
I wanted to thank you...
找到了我的朋友汉娜
for finding my friend Hanna...
体面地埋葬了她
giving her a proper burial.
我不会忘记的
I won't forget it.
敢再靠近我们  你会后悔的
Come near us again, and you will be sorry.
我可不这么想
I don't think so.
转告哈罗德  当我准备好了会联系他
Tell Harold I'll be in touch when I'm ready.
小心  小心
Easy, easy.
是丹顿・威克斯
It's Denton Weeks.
有人找上他了
Somebody got to him.
俄勒冈游戏十强
名字                                           分数                          等级
根      主导大师
俄勒冈游戏十强